<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ohm Finder</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">Ohm Finder</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- Strings used for Menu -->
    <string name="menu_help">Help</string>
    <string name="menu_history">Previous values</string>
    <string name="menu_support">Support</string>

    <!-- Strings used for first for navigation Section-->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">Ohm Finder</string>

    <!-- Strings used for second for navigation Section-->
    <string name="second_fragment_label">4 Band</string>
    <string name="four_band_resistor_model">4 Band Resistor</string>
    <string name="four_band_resistor_model_tip">2 significant digits, 1 multiplier and 1 tolerance</string>

    <!-- Strings used for third for navigation Section-->
    <string name="third_fragment_label">5 Band</string>
    <string name="five_band_resistor_model">5 Band Resistor</string>
    <string name="five_band_resistor_model_tip">3 significant digits, 1 multiplier and 1 tolerance</string>

    <!-- Strings used for fourth for navigation Section-->
    <string name="fourth_fragment_label">6 Band</string>
    <string name="six_band_resistor_model">6 Band Resistor</string>
    <string name="six_band_resistor_model_tip">3 significant digits, 1 multiplier and 2 tolerances</string>

    <!-- Strings used for results Section-->
    <string name="output_title">Output</string>
    <string name="resistor_value">Resistor value:</string>
    <string name="resistor_wvalue">Resistor value: %1$s </string>
    <string name="resistor_tolerance_value">Tolerance: ±%1$s</string>
    <string name="resistor_value_range">Range: %1$s ~ %2$s</string>
    <string name="resistor_ppm_value">PPM: %1$s</string>

    <!-- Strings used for band colors Section-->
    <string name="black_band">Black</string>
    <string name="brown_band">Brown</string>
    <string name="red_band">Red</string>
    <string name="orange_band">Orange</string>
    <string name="yellow_band">Yellow</string>
    <string name="green_band">Green</string>
    <string name="blue_band">Blue</string>
    <string name="violet_band">Violet</string>
    <string name="grey_band">Grey</string>
    <string name="white_band">White</string>
    <string name="gold_band">Gold</string>
    <string name="silver_band">Silver</string>

   <!-- General and tips Section-->
    <string name="resistor_parameters_title">Resistor Parameters</string>
    <string name="resistor_parameters_subtitle">Select the colors to determine the value and tolerance of the resistor</string>
    <string name="tip_resistor_reading">You read resistor bands beginning with the end that has the most bands.</string>
    <string name="tip_resistor_model">Choose the resistor model based on the number of bands</string>
    <string name="first_band_hint">First band color</string>
    <string name="second_band_hint">Second band color</string>
    <string name="multiplier_band_hint">Multiplier band color</string>
    <string name="tolerance_band_hint">Tolerance band color</string>
    <string name="third_band_hint">Third band color</string>
    <string name="ppm_band_hint">PPM</string>
    <string name="button_go">Go</string>
    <string name="resistor_delete_dialog_title">Delete resistor?</string>
    <string name="resistor_delete_dialog_message">This action can not be undone.</string>
    <string name="resistor_delete_dialog_yes">Delete</string>
    <string name="resistor_delete_dialog_no">Cancel</string>
    <string name="resistor_deleted">Resistor deleted</string>
    <string name="resistor_not_deleted">Resistor not deleted</string>
    <string name="resistor_created_at">Created at: %1$s</string>
    <string name="resistor_history">Previous resistors</string>
    <string name="resistor_history_empty">No previous resistor</string>
    <string name="resistor_history_size">%1$d of %2$d items</string>
    <string name="button_reset_description">Reset all fields</string>

    <!-- Help Section -->
    <string name="help_title">Help</string>
    <string name="help_introduction">
        <Data>
            <![CDATA[
                The <b><font color="#CC8D46">Ohm Finder</font></b> app is your companion for working with resistors! Whether you\'re a student, engineer, or a DIY electronics enthusiast,
                <b>Ohm Finder</b> simplifies decoding resistor color codes, giving you precise resistance values in just seconds.

                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">What is a Resistor?</font></b>
                <br/><br/>A resistor is an essential electrical component that restricts the flow of electric current in a circuit.
                It plays a vital role in controlling voltage and current levels, protecting sensitive components, and dividing voltages.
                Resistors are coded with colored bands following international standards, such as <b>IEC 60062:2016</b>, enabling easy identification of their resistance values and tolerances without using measurement tools.
                <br/><br/>The color bands represent significant digits, a multiplier, and tolerance. In some cases, additional bands specify reliability or temperature coefficient.
                This coding system is indispensable for ensuring the correct application of resistors in electronic circuits.

                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">Understanding the Color Band System</font></b>
                <br/><br/>The resistor color code system uses bands of colors to indicate the resistance value, tolerance, and occasionally, the temperature coefficient of a resistor.
                There are three main resistor color coding systems: <b>4-Band</b>, <b>5-Band</b>, and <b>6-Band</b>.
                <br/><br/>Each system utilizes a specific number of colored bands, where each band conveys critical information about the resistor\'s characteristics,
                such as resistance value and tolerance. Understanding these codes is key to accurately determining the resistor\'s specifications and ensuring proper usage in electronic circuits.

                <br/><br/>To correctly read these codes, hold the resistor so the color bands are viewed from left to right.
                A slight gap between the third band and the tolerance band typically indicates the correct reading direction. Here\'s an example to illustrate:
            ]]>
        </Data>
    </string>
    <string name="help_example">
        <Data>
            <![CDATA[
                <br/>1. The <font color="#FF2100">first</font> (red) significant figure of component value (left side)
                <br/>2. The <font color="#6967CE">second</font> (violet) significant figure (some precision resistors have a third significant figure, and thus five bands)
                <br/>3. The decimal <font color="#528F65">multiplier</font> (green) (number of trailing zeroes, or power of 10 multiplier)
                <br/>4. If present, indicates <font color="#C08327">tolerance</font> (gold) of value in percent (no band means 20%)

                <br/>It is safe to state that the reading should <b><font color="#CC8D46">start beginning with the end that has the most bands.</font></b>
            ]]>
        </Data>
    </string>
    <string name="help_color_table">
        <Data>
            <![CDATA[
                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">Color code table</font></b>
                <br/><br/>The IEC 60062:2016 provides coding methods for the resistance or capacitance value and its tolerance,
                including colour coding for resistors. It also provides date code systems suitable for the marking of small components. The colors is as follows:
            ]]>
        </Data>
    </string>

    <string name="help_four_band_resistor_introduction">
        <Data>
            <![CDATA[
                The four band resistor is the most common variation. These resistors have two bands for the resistance value, one multiplier and one tolerance band.
                <br/>To read a four-banded resistor, you\'ll want to look for the colored bands on one side of the resistor and follow these steps:

                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">1. Identify the bands and their meaning</font></b>
                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">2. Read the color bands in sequence</font></b>
                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">3. Decode each band\'s color using a color chart</font></b>
                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">4. Combine the values of the first two bands, multiply by the factor represented by the third band, and apply the tolerance from the fourth band.</font></b>
                <br/><br/>
                Example
            ]]>
        </Data>
    </string>
    <string name="help_four_band_resistor_example">
        <Data>
            <![CDATA[
                In the example shown above, the 4 bands are
                <font color="#FF2100">red</font>,
                <font color="#6967CE">violet</font>,
                <font color="#528F65">green</font> and
                <font color="#fab66e">gold</font>. By using the color code chart, one finds that <font color="#FF2100">red</font> stands for 2 and <font color="#6967CE">violet</font> for 7.
                The third band is the multiplier, with <font color="#528F65">green</font> representing a multiplier value of 6. Therefore, the value of this resistor is 27 * 100k = 2.70 MΩ. The gold band means that the resistor has a tolerance of 5%.
                The resistance value lies therefore between 2.565000 Ω and 2.835000 Ω (2.70M ± 5%).
                <br/><br/>If the tolerance band is left blank, the result is a 3 band resistor. This means that the resistance value remains the same, <font color="#CC8D46">but the tolerance is 20%</font>.
            ]]>
        </Data>
    </string>

    <string name="help_five_band_resistor_introduction">
        <Data>
            <![CDATA[
                Five-band resistors are a variation of four-band resistors, designed for applications requiring high precision. These resistors include an additional band to indicate a third significant digit, providing greater accuracy.
                <br/>To read a five-banded resistor, you\'ll want to look for the colored bands on one side of the resistor and follow these steps:

                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">1. Identify the larger gap between the third band and the last band, which is the tolerance band.</font></b>
                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">2. Start from the side closest to the significant digits and move towards the tolerance band.</font></b>
                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">3. Decode each band\'s color using a color chart</font></b>
                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">4. Combine the values of the first three bands, multiply by the factor represented by the fourth band, and apply the tolerance from the fifth band.</font></b>
                <br/><br/>
                Example
            ]]>
        </Data>
    </string>
    <string name="help_five_band_resistor_example">
        <Data>
            <![CDATA[
                In the example shown above, the 5 bands are
                <font color="#FF2100">red</font>,
                <font color="#FF2100">red</font>,
                <font color="#000">black</font>
                <font color="#FF6400">orange</font> and
                <font color="#512627">brown</font>. By using the color code chart, one finds that first and second color <font color="#FF2100">red</font> stands for 2.
                The third significant digit is <font color="#000">black</font>, value of 0. The multiplier band is <font color="#FF6400">orange</font>. Therefore, the value of this resistor is 220 * 1k = 220 kΩ.
                The <font color="#512627">brown</font> band means that the resistor has a tolerance of 1%.
                The resistance value lies therefore between 217.800 Ω and 222.200 Ω (200k ± 1%).
                <br/><br/>If the tolerance band is left blank, the result is a 3 band resistor. This means that the resistance value remains the same, <font color="#CC8D46">but the tolerance is 20%</font>.
            ]]>
        </Data>
    </string>

    <string name="help_six_band_resistor_introduction">
        <Data>
            <![CDATA[
                Six-band resistors are designed for ultra-precise applications and have an additional sixth band that specifies the temperature coefficient.
                <br/>To read a four-banded resistor, you\'ll want to look for the colored bands on one side of the resistor and follow these steps:

                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">1. Identify the larger gap between the third band and the fifth band. The fifth band is the tolerance band, and the sixth band is the temperature coefficient.</font></b>
                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">2. Start from the side closest to the significant digits and read towards the tolerance and temperature coefficient bands.</font></b>
                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">3. Decode each band\'s color using a color chart</font></b>
                <br/><br/><b><font color="#CC8D46">4. Combine the values of the first three bands, multiply by the factor represented by the fourth band, and apply the tolerance from the fifth band.</font></b>
                <br/><br/>
                Example
            ]]>
        </Data>
    </string>
    <string name="help_six_band_resistor_example">
        <Data>
            <![CDATA[
                In the example shown above, the 6 bands are
                <font color="#FF6400">orange</font>,
                <font color="#FF6400">orange</font>,
                <font color="#000">black</font>,
                <font color="#FF6400">orange</font>,
                <font color="#fab66e">gold</font> and
                <font color="#512627">brown</font>. By using the color code chart, one finds that <font color="#FF6400">orange</font> stands for 3 and <font color="#000">black</font> for 0.
                The fourth band is the multiplier, with <font color="#FF6400">orange</font> representing a multiplier value of 3. The <font color="#fab66e">gold</font> is tolerance value of 5% and PPM <font color="#512627">brown</font>, value of 100 ppm.
                Therefore, the value of this resistor is 330 * 1k = 330 kΩ.
                The resistance value lies therefore between 313.500 Ω and 346.500 Ω (330k ± 5% 100ppm).
            ]]>
        </Data>
    </string>
</resources>